Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1919-1973 (Box 1-11)
  - Congreso Internacional de Americanistas, 31st, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Conklin, Harold Colyer, [ca. 1971] (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Psychology, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Cooper, John M., 1926-1943 (Box 2)
  - Cordwell, Justine, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Cosmos Club, Washington, DC, 1950, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Cottrell, Leonard S., Jr., 1941-1959 (Box 2)
  - Council on Intercultural Relations, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Cramer, Maurice B., 1957 (Box 2)
  - Cranbrook Institute of Science, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Crane, Robert I., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Cressman, Luther S., 1955-1962 (Box 2)
  - Criterion Books, Inc., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Current Anthropology, 1958-1963 (Box 2)
  - Dallstream, Schiff, Hardin, Waite & Dorschel, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Darnell, Regna, 1966-1976 (Box 3)
    -See also Ser. VI, G (Darnell, Regna-- Athabasca, Edmonton, Yellowknife)
  - Datta-Majumder, Nabendu, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Davidson (Box 3)
    -See Ser.I, Parsons, Elsie Clews
  - Davidson, David S., 1928, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Davis, Kingsley, 1942-1948 (Box 3)
  - Davis, Stanley M., 1963 (Box 3)
  - Day, Gordon Malcolm, 1952-1970 (Box 3)
  - De Josselin de Jong, J.P.B., 1926 (Box 3)
  - De Laguna, Frederica, 1946, 1958-1975 (Box 3)
    -See also Ser.I, Indiana University Press
    -See also Ser.I, Spier, Leslie
    -See also Ser.I, Whilte, Philip L.
  - De Laguna, Grace A., 1962 (Box 3)
  - Densmore, Frances, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Denver Art Museum, 1946 (Box 3)
  - De Schweinitz, K., 1943 (Box 3)
  - Despret, J. Louise, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Devereux, George, 1939-1966 (Box 3)
  - DeVilliers, David Z., 1953 (Box 3)
  - DeVore, Irven, 1958 (Box 3)
  - DeVos, George A., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Dewdney, Selwyn, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Dexter, Ralph W., 1949 (Box 3)
  - Diamond, Stanley, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Dickson, Frederick S., 1922-1926 (Box 3)
  - Dietrich, Donald H., 1950 (Box 3)
  - Diggs, Irene, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius G., 1962 (Box 3)
  - Doll, Eugene E., 1947 (Box 3)
  - Dollard, John, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Donath, Fred, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Dorsey Press, Inc., 1961 (Box 3)
  - Dorson, Richard M., 1953 (Box 3)
  - Douglas, Eric, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Dowling, Sheila, 1964-1969 (Box 3)
  - Downing, Robert W., 1956 (Box 3)
  - Dozier, Edward, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Dresden, Mark J., 1960 (Box 3)
  - Driver, Harold E., 1952 (Box 3)
  - Du Bois, Cora, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Dumouchel, Paul A., 1946 (Box 3)
  - Dunn, Sheila, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Eaton, Joseph W., 1949 (Box 3)
  - Eaton, Walter H., 1946 (Box 3)
  - Eayrs, S. Lowell, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Eckelberry, R.H., 1949 (Box 3)
  - Edel, Abraham, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Edman, Irwin, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Egeland, Janice A., 1972 (Box 3)
  - Eggan, Frederick R., 1942-1965 (Box 3)
  - Ehrich, Robert W., 1957-1962 (Box 3)
  - Eichhorn, Erika (Box 3)
    -See Ser.I, Bouguignon, Erika Eichhorn
  - Eiseley, Loren, 1941-1962 (Box 3)
    -See also Ser.I, Eldridge, Seba
  - Eiseley, Mabel (Mrs. Loren C.), [1950] (Box 3)
  - Eisenstadt, S.N., 1962 (Box 3)
  - Eldridge, Seba, 1944 (Box 3)
    -See also Ser.I, Eiseley, Loren
  - Eliot, Thomas D., 1950 (Box 3)
  - Embree, John F., 1949 (Box 3)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Encyclopedia of the American Indian, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Endleman, Robert, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Ennis, Elisabeth L. (Mrs. Merlin W.), 1952 (Box 3)
  - Erickson, Vincent, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Eshleman, Robert F., 1956 (Box 3)
  - Ewers, John C., 1946 (Box 3)
  - Ewing, James H., 1956 (Box 3)
  - Fagg, Bernard, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Fagg, Fred D., 1946 (Box 3)
  - Farrell Lines, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Fauset, Arthur Huff, 1955-1957 (Box 3)
  - Fauteux, Aegidius, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Fejos, Paul, 1948-1949 (Box 3)
  - Feldman, Harold, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Felix, Arthur, [ca. 1930] (Box 3)
  - Fellows, Muriel H., 1947 (Box 3)
  - Feng, Chia-sheng, 1944 (Box 3)
  - Feng, H.Y., 1945-1946 (Box 3)
  - Fenton, William Nelson, 1946-1969 (Box 3)
    -See also Ser.I, Beck, Horace P., Jr.
  - Fernberger, Samuel W., 1938 (Box 3)
    -Photos removed to Ser.VI, G
  - [Fewkes, Vladimir J.], 1926, 1937, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Fiddle, Seymour, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Field, Lewis W., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Finch, Henry A., 1945 (Box 3)
  - Fischer, John L., 1959-1964 (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Margaret (Mrs. Lloyd), 1943-195? (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Seymour, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Flink, James J., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Florida State University, 1969 (Box 3)
    Smith, Hale G.
  - Fogelson, Ray, 1957-1974 (Box 3)
  - Fogg, John M., 1942 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Forde, Daryll, 1949-1960 (Box 3)
  - Forest History Society, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Foundations' Fund for Research in Psychiatry, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Frachtenberg, Leo J., 1924 (Box 3)
  - Frank, Lawrence K., 1941-1954 (Box 3)
  - Frankford Friends Meeting, Philadelphia, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Franklin and Marshall College, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Frantz, Charles, 1956-1970 (Box 3)
  - Freeman, Derek, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Freeman, Elsie T., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Freeman, John F., 1957 (Box 3)
  - Freilich, Morris, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Fried, Jacob, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
  - Fried, Paul E., 1947 (Box 3)
  - Friedl, Ernestine, 1945, 1954-1967 (Box 3)
  - Friedrich, Paul, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Fuller, Charles Edward, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Fuzishima, Kazuma, 1967 (Box 3)
    -See also Ser.I, Linton, Ralph
  - Gahs, Alexander, 1928 (Box 4)
    in German
  - Galston, Iago, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Gamble, John T., 1947 (Box 4)
  - Gardner, George E., 1938 (Box 4)
  - Gayton, Ann H., 1945-1950 (Box 4)
  - George, Katherine Archibald, 1945, 1951-1960 (Box 4)
  - Georgetown University, 1961 (Box 4)
    Bunn, Edward B.
    Steinbach, Richard A.
  - Giffond, E.W., 1924-1928 (Box 4)
  - Gilford, Duff and M.E., 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Giller, Herbert and Renata, 1959-1962 (Box 4)
  - Gillin, John Philip, 1942-1971 (Box 4)
    -See also Ser.I, American Anthropological Society. Symposium on Human Nature, 1952
  - Gilmore, Melvin, 1933 (Box 4)
  - Gingold, Arrama, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Glazer, Nathan, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Goddard, David R., 1964 (Box 4)
  - Godfrey, Marian (Mrs. William S.), 1945 (Box 4)
  - Goffman, Irwin W., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Gold, Dolores, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Goldenweiser, Alexander A., 1936 (Box 4)
  - Goldman, Irving, 1951 (Box 4)
  - Goldschmidt, Walter R., 1948, 1950-1966 (Box 4)
  - Goldstein, Kenneth S., 1970 (Box 4)
  - Goldstein, W.M., 1944 (Box 4)
  - Golomshtok, Eugene A., 1946-1949 (Box 4)
  - Goodenough, Ward H., 1949 (Box 4)
  - Goodman, Mary Ellen, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Gordon, George Byron, 1926 (Box 4)
  - Gorer, Geoffrey, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Gores, Catherine, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Gough, H.G., 1949 (Box 4)
  - Grass, Llewellyn, [ca. 1940] (Box 4)
  - Gray, David, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Great Lakes Indian Agency, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Green, Jesse D., 1964 (Box 4)
  - Green, John C., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Greenman, Emerson Frank, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Greenway, John, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Gregory, James R., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Griffin, William and Joyce, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Grigolia, Alexander, 1943-1968 (Box 4)
  - Grinnell, George Bird, 1924-1926 (Box 4)
  - The Grolier Society, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Gruber, Jacob W., 1955-1972 (Box 4)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1956-1972 (Box 4)
    Ray, Gordon N.
    -See also Ser.I, Moe, Henry Allen
  - Guha, B.S., 1958 (Box 4)
  - The Guide to Psychiatric and Phychological Literature, 1955 (Box 4)
    Slochower, Harry
  - Gulick, John, 1956-1958 (Box 4)
  - Gunther, Erna, 1950-1954 (Box 4)
  - Gurdin, J. Barry, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Guthrie, Lillian, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Haddon, A.C., 1926 (Box 4)
  - Hadzsit, 1929 (Box 4)
  - Hagar, Stansbury, 1924 (Box 4)
  - Haggard, Ernest A., 1972 (Box 4)
  - Haines, George, 1943-1946 (Box 4)
  - Hall, Edward T., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Hallet, R.E., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Hallowell, Dorothy Kern (Box 4)
    -See Ser.I, Hallowell, William H.
  - Hallowell, Maude Frame, 1959-1981 (Box 4)
    Rogers, Mary Black
  - Hallowell, William H., 1954-1961 (Box 4)
    Hallowell, Dorothy Kern
  - Halpert, Herbert, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Hamell, Janvier Lamar, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Hamer, John H., 1964 (Box 4)
  - Hammond, Peter B., 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Hannah, Sam Gray Wolf, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Haram, Harold, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Haring, Douglas G., 1949, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc., 1959-1964 (Box 4)
    -See also Ser.I, Baller, Warren R.
  - Harriman, Philip L., 1938 (Box 4)
  - Harrington, John P., 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - Harris, Jack, 1946-1953 (Box 4)
  - Harris, Louis, 1923 (Box 4)
  - Harris, R. Laird, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Harris, Zellig S., 1945, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Harrison, Everett, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Harrison, John P., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Harrison, Shelby M., 1946 (Box 4)
  - Harshberger, John W. (Box 4)
  - Hart, C.W.M., 1952-1954 (Box 4)
  - Hart, Harold H., 1960 (Box 4)
    -See Ser.I, Hart Publishing Co., Inc.
  - Hart Publishing Co., Inc. (Box 4)
    Hart, Harold H.
  - Hart, William A., 1955 (Box 4)
  - Harvard University, 1961 (Box 4)
    -See also Ser.I, Pusey, Nathan M.
  - Harvard University. Peabody Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology, 1954-1955 (Box 4)
  - Harvard University Press, 1945-1967 (Box 4)
  - Hause, Helen, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Haverford College, 1956-1960 (Box 4)
  - Hawley, Florence, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Hawthorn, Harry, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Hay, Thomas Hamilton, 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - Hays, H.R., 1959 (Box 4)
  - D.C. Heath and Company, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Hebert, Bernard L., 1954-1955 (Box 4)
  - Hector, Shirley, 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Heinemann, Robert D., 1953 (Box 4)
  - Helm, June, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Henderson, Gerald M., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Henry, Jules, 1938-1954 (Box 4)
    -See also Ser.I, American Orthopsychiatric Association
  - Henry, William E., 1944-1945 (Box 4)
  - Herskovits, Melville Jean, 1943-1961 (Box 4)
  - Hertz, Marguerite R., 1941-1948 (Box 4)
  - Herzog, George, 1934-1949 (Box 4)
  - Heye, George G., 1920-1937 (Box 4)
  - Highland, Genevieve A., 1946-1965 (Box 4)
  - Hilger, M. Inez, 1945-1954 (Box 4)
  - Himelhoch, Jerome (Box 4)
    -See Ser.I, Social Problems
  - Hirning, L. Clovis, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Hoben, Allan, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Hockett, Charles F., 1949 (Box 4)
  - Hodge, F.W. (Box 4)
    -See Ser.I, Museum of American Indian, New York
  - Hodgen, Margaret T., 1960-1963 (Box 4)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Holbrook, Leona, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Holland, William R., 1955 (Box 4)
  - Holmberg, Allan R., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1963-1967 (Box 4)
  - Honigman, John J., 1944-1970 (Box 4)
  - Honigsheim, Paul, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Honkavaara, Sylvia, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Hopper, Rex D., 1953 (Box 4)
  - Horosz, William, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Howard, George D., 1946 (Box 4)
  - Howell, Francis Clark, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Howells, W.W., 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Hsu, Francis L.K., 1946-1962 (Box 5)
  - Hudak, Vilma, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Huden, John C., 1955 (Box 5)
  - Hudson's Bay Company, 1931-1940 (Box 5)
  - Hughes, Helen MacGill, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Human Relations Area Files, 1959-1964 (Box 5)
  - Hunt, Robert C., 1966 (Box 5)
  - Hunt, William A., 1955 (Box 5)
  - Hurvich, Marvin, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Hwang, Chien-hou, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Hydes, W.W., 1950 (Box 5)
  - Hymes, Dell, 1965-1967 (Box 5)
  - Imanishi, Kinji, 1958-1962 (Box 5)
  - Indiana University Press, 1962 (Box 5)
    -See also Ser.I, De Laguna, Frederica
  - Inkeles, Alex, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Research on Crime and Delinquency, Inc., 1955-1956 (Box 5)
  - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1956, 1967 (Box 5)
  - International Congress of Social Psychiatry Bierer, Joshua, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
    -See also Ser.I, Opler, Marvin K.
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - International Universities Press, Inc., 1963 (Box 5)
  - Inverarity, Robert Bruce, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Irwin, Orvis C., 1946 (Box 5)
  - Ishizu, Teruji, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Isleib, Howard F., 1956 (Box 5)
  - James, Bernard J., 1963 (Box 5)
  - Jay, Phyllis, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Jefferson Medical College, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Jennings, Francis P., 1959 (Box 5)
  - Jennings, Jesse D., 1960-1962 (Box 5)
  - Johns Hopkins University. School of Advanced International Studies, 1961 (Box 5)
    Johnson, E.A.J.
  - Johnson, E.A.J. (Box 5)
    -See Ser.I, Johns Hopkins University. School of Advanced International Studies
  - Johnson, Frederick, 1943-1955 (Box 5)
    -See also Ser.I, Satterthwaite, Linton
  - Johnson, Justine, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, William, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Jonitis, Peter P., 1954-1963 (Box 5)
  - Journal of American Folklore, 1946-1955 (Box 5)
  - The Journal of Higher Education, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
  - Journal of Projective Techniques, 1947-1954 (Box 5)
  - Journal of the History of the Behavioral Sciences, 1964-1968 (Box 5)
    Watson, Robert I.
  - Kaplan, Bernard, 1955-1963 (Box 5)
  - Kaplan, Bernice A., 1951 (Box 5)
  - Kaplan, Bert, 1957-1963 (Box 5)
  - Kardiner, Abram, 1938-1947 (Box 5)
  - Katcher, Joan, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Katz, Sander, 1946-1947 (Box 5)
  - Katz, Solomon, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Kay, Brian Ross, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Kayser, Joyce, 1961-1964 (Box 5)
  - Kelley, Douglas M., 1947 (Box 5)
  - Kelly, Eric P. (Box 5)
  - Kennard, Edward A., 1958 (Box 5)
  - Kerner, Oliver J.B., 1949 (Box 5)
  - Kerr, Madeline, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Kiev, Ari, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - King, C. Harold, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Kirschenbaum, Rose Eve, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Kitagawa, Joseph M., 1962 (Box 5)
  - Klonower, Henry, 1944 (Box 5)
  - Klopfer, Bruno, 1941-1958 (Box 5)
    -See also Ser.I, Thompson, Laura
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1941-1958 (Box 5)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1945-1963 (Box 5)
  - Knowles, Nathaniel, 1944-1945 (Box 5)
  - Koss, Joan D., 1956-1967 (Box 5)
  - Krakauer, Daniel, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Krause, Fritz, 1927 (Box 5)
  - Kroeber, Alfred L., 1942-1956 (Box 5)
  - Krogman, W.M., 1949 (Box 5)
  - Krout, Morris H., 1947 (Box 5)
  - Kutsche, Paul, 1956-1962 (Box 5)
    -Photo removed to Ser. VI, G
  - Kutztown State College, 1968 (Box 5)
  - La Barre, Weston, 1942-1955 (Box 5)
  - La Farge, Oliver, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Lagasse, Jean H., 1959 (Box 5)
  - Laing, James T., 1961 (Box 5)
  - Lally, Ann, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Lamb Hoover, Mandi, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Lambert, R.S., 1953 (Box 5)
    -See also Ser.II, Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, "The Shaking Tent"
  - Landes, Ruth, 1948-1957 (Box 5)
  - Lane, Warren, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Langness, Lewis L., 1964-1970 (Box 5)
    -See also Ser.I, Seattle Anthropological Society
  - Lantis, Margaret, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - Lantz, Herman, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Lassner, Rudolf, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Laufer, Berthold, 1922-1926 (Box 5)
  - Laurent, Stephen, 1936-1956 (Box 5)
  - Lauria, Anthony, Jr., 1960 (Box 5)
  - Leach, MacEdward, 1944-1947 (Box 6)
  - Leary, James R., 1956 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Alfred McClung, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Charles, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Lee, D. Demetracopoulou, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Frank F., 1960 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Helen C., 1947, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Irving J., 1948 (Box 6)
  - Leechman, Douglas, 1945-1956 (Box 6)
  - Leeds, Anthony, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Lefferts, Marie (Mrs. Walter), 1942 (Box 6)
  - Leibovici, Marcel, 1959-1962 (Box 6)
    some in French
  - Leighton, Alexander H., 1960 (Box 6)
  - Leighton, Dorothea C., 1938-1963 (Box 6)
  - Leme Lopes, José, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Lemert, Edwin M., 1952 (Box 6)
  - Lesage, Germain, 1944-1946 (Box 6)
  - Lesser, Alexander, 1943, 1947-1965 (Box 6)
  - Levinson, Daniel, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Levy, Harry L., 1958 (Box 6)
  - Levy, Marion J., Jr., 1962 (Box 6)
  - Lewis, James, 1950-1952 (Box 6)
  - Lewis, Oscar, 1946-1953 (Box 6)
  - Libby, Dorothy, 1960-1962 (Box 6)
  - Lidz, Theodore, 1941-1942 (Box 6)
  - Lidz, Victor, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Linder, Robert M., 1942 (Box 6)
  - Lindzey, Gardner, 1956-1964 (Box 6)
  - Linton, Ralph, 1928-1953 (Box 6)
    -See also Ser.I, Fuzishima, Kazuma
  - Llewellyn, Sarah, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Locher, G.W., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Lockett, Robert L., 1960 (Box 6)
  - Lohmann, Carl A., 1947 (Box 6)
  - Long, John S., 1972 (Box 6)
  - Lounsbury, Floyd G., 1957 (Box 6)
  - Lowie, Robert H., 1946-1950 (Box 6)
  - Lowrey, Lawson G., 1938 (Box 6)
  - Lurie, Nancy Oestreich, 1955-1962 (Box 6)
  - McBride, Katharine, 1943 (Box 6)
  - McClellan, Catharine, 1964 (Box 6)
  - McClelland, David, 1965 (Box 6)
  - McClelland, George William, 1947 (Box 6)
  - McClure, Diane C., n.d. (Box 6)
  - MacCurdy, George Grant, 1924-1926 (Box 6)
  - MacDonald, J. Lorne, 1964 (Box 6)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1960-1963 (Box 6)
  - Macgregor, Gordon, 1942 (Box 6)
  - McGurk, Frank C.J., 1954 (Box 6)
    contains microcards
  - McHarg, Ian L., 1963 (Box 6)
  - McIlwraith, T[om] F., 1936-1960 (Box 6)
  - MacInnes, T.R., 1950 (Box 6)
  - McKennan, Robert A., 1958 (Box 6)
  - MacKinnon, Donald A., 1945-1958 (Box 6)
  - Macklin, Barbara June, 1956-1966 (Box 6)
  - MacLeod, Christie, 1936 (Box 6)
  - MacLeod, Robert Brodie, 1950-1958 (Box 6)
  - McMillan, Norman D., 1971 (Box 6)
  - MacMillan Company, 1965 (Box 6)
  - MacRae, Duncan, Jr., 1961 (Box 6)
  - Mahran, Adel, 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - Mallery, Arlington H., 1957 (Box 6)
  - Mandelbaum, David G., 1946, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Mangin, William, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Manners, Robert A., 1961-1966 (Box 6)
  - Manning, T.H., 1943 (Box 6)
  - Manseau, J.A., 1926 (Box 6)
  - Margetts, Edward L., 1960-1965 (Box 6)
  - Marmour, Judd, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Marriage Council of Philadelphia, 1952-1956 (Box 6)
    Mudd, Emily H.
  - Mars, Louis, 1942-1947 (Box 6)
  - Marseille, Walter W., 1945-1946 (Box 6)
  - Martin, Edward, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Martin, Paul S., 1947 (Box 6)
  - Mason, J. Alden, 1947, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Mason, Leonard, 1962-1965 (Box 6)
  - Masta, Henry Lorne, 1923-1933 (Box 6)
  - Mathiasse, Thekel, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Mathis, Donald B., 1961 (Box 6)
  - Maude, H.E., 1964 (Box 6)
  - May, Rollo, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Mead, Margaret, 1941-1966 (Box 6)
    Wishner, Julius
  - Mechling, W.H., 1924 (Box 6)
  - Medalia, Nahum Z., 1968-1971 (Box 6)
  - Mednick, Melvin, 1953-1955 (Box 6)
  - Meggers, Betty Jane, 1943-1945 (Box 6)
  - Meighan, Clement W., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Meigs, Anna, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Mekeel, H. Scudder, 1942-1944 (Box 6)
  - Menaker, Esther, 1953-1973 (Box 6)
  - Messing, Simon D., 1952-1959 (Box 6)
  - Metraux, Rhoda, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Meyer, Heinrich, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Michail, Ronald, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Michelson, Truman, 1920-1935 (Box 6)
  - Michigan. Department of Mental Health, 1959 (Box 6)
    Andrew, Gwen
  - Microcard Foundation, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Midlo, Charles, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Miller, Valentin, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Mintz, Sidney W., 1949 (Box 6)
  - Mitchell, Marian, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Mitchell, Roy Angus, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1945, 1963 (Box 6)
    -See also Ser.I, Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
  - Montague, M.F. Ashley (Box 6)
    -See Ser.I, Ashley-Montagu, M.F.
  - Mook, Maurice Allison, 1942-1945, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Mora, José Ferrater, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Mordini, Antonio, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Morenus, Nan D., 1947 (Box 6)
  - Morgan, Richard G., 1948 (Box 6)
  - Morin, Gerard, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christine C., 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - Morrow, Glenn R., 1947-1949 (Box 6)
  - Mosner, Beatrice, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Moustakas, Clark E., 1954-1955 (Box 6)
  - Movius, Hallam L., 1949 (Box 6)
  - Mowrer, O. Hobart, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
  - MSS Educational Publishing Company, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Mudd, Emily H. (Box 6)
    -See Ser.I, Marriage Council of Philadelphia
  - Muensterberger, Warner, 1945, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Murdock, George P., 1941-1955 (Box 6)
  - Murphey, Murray G., 1963-1966 (Box 6)
    -See also Ser.I, Raemsch, Bruce E.
  - Murphy, Allen H., 1947 (Box 6)
  - Murra, John V., 1949 (Box 6)
  - Murray, Henry A., 1953 (Box 6)
  - Murray, John J., 1946 (Box 6)
  - Museum of the American Indian, New York, 1921-1928 (Box 6)
    Hodge, F.W.
  - Musser, Paul H., 1949 (Box 6)
  - Myers, Edna, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Myers, Frank A., 1960 (Box 6)
  - Nadel, S.F, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Naroll, Raoul, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Nash, Dennison J., 1952-1964 (Box 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1955-1971 (Box 7)
  - National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, Inc., 1950 (Box 7)
  - The National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1951 (Box 7)
  - National Museum of Canada, 1928-1971 (Box 7)
  - National Research Council, 1938-1957 (Box 7)
  - National Research Council. Committee on Food Habits, 1942-1943 (Box 7)
  - National Research Council. Committee on Personality in Relation to Culture, 1935-1940 (Box 7)
  - National Research Council. Committee on Primary Records, 1957-1960; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1957 (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1958-1960 (Box 7)
  - National Science Foundation, 1958-1964 (Box 7)
  - Naturalists' Directory, 1944, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Nelson, Benjamin, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Nelson, C.A., 1942 (Box 7)
  - Nelson, Mollie Dellis, 1958-1959 (Box 7)
  - Nelson, N.C., 1924-1925 (Box 7)
  - Nelson's Encyclopedia, 1947 (Box 7)
  - The New Catholic Encyclopedia, 1964 (Box 7)
  - New Directions, 1946 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey State Hospital at Trenton, 1951 (Box 7)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1948-1962 (Box 7)
  - Newberry Library, Chicago, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Niguers, Ruth Hill, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Nimkoff, M.F., 1959 (Box 7)
  - Nippgen, J., 1928 (Box 7)
  - Noon, John Alfred, 1942-1945, 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Northrop, Filmer S.C., 1961 (Box 7)
  - Northwestern University, 1943-1946 (Box 7)
    -See also Ser.I, Bourguignon, Erika Eichhorn
  - Noyes, C. Reinhold, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Oberly, Sherman, 1946 (Box 7)
  - O'Brien, Denise, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Oder, Evelyn, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Official Detective Stories, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Ohio State Archaeological and Historical Society, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Ohnuki-Tierney, Emiko, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Olafson, Sigfus, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Onderdonk, Andrew J., 1946 (Box 7)
  - O'Neale, Lila M., 1929 (Box 7)
  - Onujagbe, Stephen O., 1963 (Box 7)
  - Opler, Marvin K., 1942-1964 (Box 7)
    -See also Ser.I, International Congress of Social Psychiatry
  - Opler, Morris Edward, 1949, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Orlansky, Harold, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Orr, Francis, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Osgood, Cornelius, 1946, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Ottenberg, Simon, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Owen, Roger C., 1965 (Box 7)
  - Oxford University Press, 1940, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Palmatary, Helen Constance, [ca. 1941] (Box 7)
  - Panadis, Theo, 1931-1932 (Box 7)
  - Pancoast, Elinor, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - Pantheon Books, Inc., 1946 (Box 7)
  - Paproth, Hans Joachim, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
    some in German
  - Parapsychology Foundation, Inc., 1962 (Box 7)
  - Park, Willard Z., 1944 (Box 7)
  - Parker, Seymour, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Parkins, C. Richard, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Parmenter, Ross, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Parsons, Elsie Clews Davidson, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Patai, Raphael, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Paul, Benjamin D., 1947-1956 (Box 7)
  - Pearce, Roy Harvey, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Pennsylvania School of Social Work, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Pepper, George, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Peters, William E., Jr., 1946 (Box 7)
  - Peterson, Alberta (Box 7)
    -See Ser.I, Bourguignon, Erika Eichhorn
  - Petrullo, Vincenzo, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia (city), 1958-1961 (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia Anthropological Society, 1948-1964, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Folder 1, 1948-1961 (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1962-1964, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia Psychiatric Society, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia. School District, 1942 (Box 7)
    -See also Ser.III, "Racial Discrimination"--Lecture
  - Phillips, Leslie, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Phillips, William A., 1954 (Box 7)
  - Pi Gamma Mu, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Pihlblad, C. Terence, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Pilbeam, David, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Piotrowski, Zygmunt A., 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Pirie, Margaret C., 1951 (Box 7)
  - Pointon, James, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Pomfret, John E., 1965 (Box 7)
  - Pommerehnke, Harald, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Posey, Rollin B., 1945 (Box 7)
  - Potash, Herbert, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Potter, Jack M., 1968 (Box 7)
  - Potter, Lloyd, 1946 (Box 7)